All right, we'll call to order about regular meeting of the City Council for Tuesday, January 6th, 2026.
Let's get into personal appearances. We have none.
3A, Proclamation declaring January 2026 as Human Trafficking Prevention Month.
Motion to approve.
Second.
Local.
E-Step.
Bards.
Parker.
Bye.
Is anyone here for that?
I am.
Okay.
I'm sure I'm glad we put prevention in there.
Yeah.
I'm glad we put prevention in there.
Just a minute.
Dude, what are you doing?
I don't know.
Help.
Yeah.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Please.
I don't know.
Yeah.
Once they do.
Okay, don't run off because I'm in a picture on her phone and mic.
I read.
Good.
Thank you.
I'm sorry.
Is there anything?
People on the letter here.
I have a weird team here.
All right, 4A claims list.
What's to approve?
E-Step.
Hi.
Local.
4B minutes from the December 16th, 2025.
two and a half.
All right.
4 c, election resolution, CC.
Twenty.
Six.
That's the only one calling for
proclaiming an ordering a non-partisan general election in the city of
Mayama county of Ottawa, state of Oklahoma on Tuesday.
April 7, 2026, for the purpose of electing the mayor.
And this would be the opportunity for all those folks
They think they can do better in a sign-up
Most shepherds
The
4d
And we've got 4d
FG and H
Ordnance 2026
That's our 0-1 repelling section 12-156
This is another one of the will-dan recommendations to do away with antiquated
Ordnances, so these this is yet another video game
Arcade type
Ordnance that probably needs to be done away with, so I have prepared the ordinances to do away with each section of it
This may not be able to go play Donkey Kong anymore
I was about to say this guy said
That is
You have to do that at home now
Dang it
Short work
That's a better idea
Motion to approve
Second
I
Parker
4e ordnance 2026
That's 0-2 repelling section 12-157
Let's do a proof
Second
I
Parker
4a ordnance 2026-03
Repelling section 12-158
Motion to approve
Second
I
Parker
4g ordnance 2026-04
Repelling section 12-159
Motion to approve
Hi
I
Parker
4a ordnance 2026-05
Repelling section 12-160
Motion to approve
Second
I
Parker
5a ordnance 2026-05
Repelling section 12-159
Motion to approve
I
Parker
5a ordnance 2026-05
Repelling section 12-157
Repelling section 12-159
Motion to approve
I
Parker
5a ordnance 2026-05
Separate progressive
commit
brother
5a ordnance 2026-0
Right-wing
sexual
©
community supporting it, right?
So our folks did a great job putting it together,
but then we didn't know what was gonna happen,
and I really, I was blown away.
I said it at the thing.
I'm blown away by how many people came out,
supported it, and it just motivates me
to want to do it bigger and better next year.
So.
So I'm gonna follow into what they said.
The ball drop, I appreciate the same way so much
because we come up with some wild ideas sometimes,
and you guys pull them off, you know,
we come up with the idea and decide we're gonna do something
and whether it's gonna work or not,
we don't know sometimes, but you guys always make it work.
And I greatly appreciate that.
You guys put the effort in, the work in,
and you're the reason that happens.
But I think, Trenta sent me a message earlier today
that with the place where it showed 848 people
in attendance, not counting kids, of course,
that didn't have cell phones.
So, you know, we may have been close to 1,000 people there.
So I'm gonna tell a little story, too,
that I heard from that event,
and I've come from our city judge, Chuck Chestnut,
had lunch with him Friday.
He said, let me tell you a funny story.
He said, I got home.
He said, I told my wife, look at this,
they're having a ball drop downtown,
we should go to this.
She said, yeah, let's go, let's do that.
And he went off, we're away, we'll go.
He said, so next morning, he woke up,
and he fell asleep before midnight,
and he woke up next morning and pulled up his phone
and saw all the pictures and videos
that everybody had taken.
And he was like, wow, that was amazing.
There's a lot of people there,
so he went to his wife and said, look at this.
They had a great turnout down there.
And she said, yeah, we did.
I guess he went in, and he was asleep,
and he went without him, okay?
But I heard a lot from families
that it was great to have a family in the event,
because nobody around here has anything like what we did.
And of course, we couldn't have pulled it off
without the city employees, Colby Allen,
now in size studios, Justin with Pyro Brothers,
simplicity truck, smash burger,
or smash and dash, Clark smash and dash was there,
but really it was a great event.
We've got a lot of publicity from the job
and news out of it.
And I even saw people from the job
with most of the, they're coming next year,
because there's nothing like what we did
anywhere else around here.
So from minor standing, this was the only ball drop
in the whole state of Oklahoma.
So, a cool deal, a cool thing to hang your hat on.
And I don't have anything else,
so go to city manager communications.
I just have one thing, you know,
the staff has gotten some questions
as read been stolen, as read disappeared.
So, this is read down in front of anybody watching,
is wondering who that is, this is read from the library.
So, here, but let's you like to talk about that idea.
Let's do it on it.
All right, so we'll leave read a little backstory
on the read here real quick.
The bronze sculpture, once upon a time,
affectionately referred to as read by the minor club
library staff was created by OSU graduate,
Michelle Riley, from the lock of hair on his forehead
to the laces on his shoes to the expression on his face.
The attention to detail is amazing.
Ms. Riley was granted a cool ride scholarship
for Tracking Field, but after an injury sideline her,
she focused her energy into her other passion,
which was art.
In 1992, she opened a studio in gallery
in the colon theater, beautiful complex,
known for capturing the emotional spirit of her subject.
She has had numerous commissions for portraits,
or portrayals, excuse me, of notable Americans
like Maya, Angelou, thank, Angelou, Angelou, Angelou.
Angelou, and Amelia Earhart.
Her work has been featured at the Smithsonian,
Ms. Riley now resides in Nevada, so that's where
we came from.
And the reason that read is not currently set
in front of the library, he's been stolen several times.
And I think this last time he was found
at a scrap yard, somebody selling for scrap, is that all right?
The apartment here is one pound.
Oh, okay.
I guess the first time he was stolen,
he was found in a scrap yard in Missouri.
And then this last time, he was found
over north of town here or north of town
in my department.
And so there's new plans for read.
He's probably going to end up back at the library, sounds like,
that he'll be much more safe and secure.
With the new fault cameras.
With...
Yeah, I have one of his pockets.
Exactly.
All right, number nine, the German...
Motion.
It's...
Dumple.
Burns, aye.
We stand.
Roger.
Aye.